Tell us about your special skills and boasts!
We asked you about your special skills and boasts in front of Niigata Station.
Could you please stop for a moment?
Take a bath in the forelock, please.
That's fine.
JK.
I don't want everyone to be with me.
I'm carrying around my waist.
I swear, you said you went to your aunt's brother
with a new book.
I see.
These girls were at last year's NST Festival.
Members of the Niigata Commercial High School dance club.
They wear jerseys.
You mean they get mad when their seniors tell them to wear jerseys?
I don't like the idea of wearing jerseys.
I don't like that they're wearing jerseys.
We're wearing jerseys.
I don't like it.
Of course, they're good at it.
Let's do it!
They're in the dance team.
Here's proof they're good at it.
Let me see.
Wow!
Wow.
Ready?
Wow!
This is an announcement from the new Niigata Commercial High School Dance Club!
The new Niigata Commercial High School Dance Club is looking for new members!
Se-no
Good morning!
We are looking for new members!
It's a new era!
New era
Thank you very much!
We don't seem to have any sophomores in the third year.
So we were talking about how we want new students to join our club.
I'm looking forward to working with the new students.
We'll be recruiting new members on the public airwaves.
Now, this week's guests are two students from Ebisu Chugaku!
Good morning, and welcome to the morning chimes of Ebisu Chugaku!
We are Ebisu Chugaku, number 3, Mayanorika, and number 16, Ema Sakurai.
Please give them my best regards.
Three of you, two of you, on a Sunday morning in Niigata.
Thank you very much.
I look forward to working with you again this week.
Do you remember the first time you came to Niigata, Mr. Mayamon?
Yes, the first time was at the NST Festival in 2013.
Oh, is that right?
Ten years ago.
Exactly 10 years ago.
Not yet.
Wow.
That's great.
I didn't know that was possible.
I remember when I first started working at NST.
Please take a look at the photos from that time.
Wow!
It was a great success!
The rainbow color is still there.
So cute!
Which one is Mr. Oyama?
Leftmost
The leftmost one.
So cute!
Embarrassing.
It's a still picture.
It's a still image.
It's just this much of him.
It's so cute!
Where did you get this from?
This is from the NST Festival, isn't it?
This is Ms. Oyama when she came to the NST Festival.
She's so cute!
I remember it.
It was my first time to visit Niigata.
I ate Pop Yaki.
It was my first time to perform in Niigata.
I was so surprised because I didn't expect so many people to come.
I haven't seen this many people in Bandai for a long time.
I haven't seen this many people in a long time.
It's amazing!
NST Festival has this kind of power.
I'm very grateful for that.
Gattatube, a program to discover videos in Niigata and other places
This week, Rika Mayama of Shiritsu Ebisu Chugaku
and Ema Sakurai of Shiritsu Ebisu Chugaku, we'll be looking into some of the questions about Niigata!
By the way, Chikapang artists are coming to Niigata for a live tour!
By the way, many chikapang artists come to Niigata for their live tours, don't they?
Yes, there are a lot of them.
It's because it's so easy to get to from Tokyo, isn't it?
That's right.
Niigata is such a place...
Here's another rumor that's been bothering me.
I'm not sure what region it is.
There are many theories.
We've been to the station to investigate.
Let's watch the VTR!
Seino
Gattatube
What region is Niigata in?
JMA weather forecast is for Hokuriku
Electric power company is in Tohoku
NHK news is Kanto and Koshinetsu
Government offices are Kanto, Kanto Shinetsu, etc.
Different prefectures are in different parts of the country
First, we asked what people outside the prefecture think of Niigata.
What region do you think Niigata is?
Hokuriku
Is it really Koshinetsu or Hokuriku?
Koshinetsu
Hokuriku, right?
Koshinetsu, I think.
I thought it was Hokuriku.
Ishikawa or something over there.
According to the ancient classification established in the Nara period, Niigata is on the Hokuriku route.
I don't think anyone in Toyama or Fukui thinks Niigata is the same as Hokuriku.
Some people think Niigata is Tohoku.
But the relationship between the prefectures in the Hokuriku region is so deep that Niigata tends to be excluded from the group.
I know it's not Tohoku.
I'm not from Tohoku.
I'm from Tokyo.
So where would it be?
It's clear.
The Tōhoku theory has long been bruited about by Niigata people
I think I'm Tōhoku.
Niigata people always get angry with me
They don't want us to be together.
They say we're the same.
Niigata people probably don't like to be lumped in with the Tohoku people.
I'm sure you agree with that.
By the way, why did you think of Niigata and Tohoku?
Because it is a rice-producing region.
And also because of the delicious sake.
Also, when I talk to people from Niigata, I feel very close to them.
They are definitely not from the Kanto region or Koshin-En.
There are other opinions like this
I don't know if it's China or the central part of Japan.
Because there were mountains here, too.
Chubu region
Chubu region, where I've only been to Chili's class.
Kanto plus 1
Kanto plus one.
I think it's more like high school.
A little distance from high school
I went to Kanto, and it's very different from the three prefectures in Hokuriku.You go to Kanto and say that it's very different from the three Hokuriku prefectures.
You can almost see the pride of the three Hokuriku prefectures.
What do you think?
Wow, there were a lot of opinions!
In the end, we were all divided, weren't we?
That's right, everyone was different.
Hokuriku, Shinetsu, Kanto plus one.
Kanto plus one is my personal favorite
Personally, as a native of Niigata, I like Kanto plus one a lot.
Kanto plus one... yes, I think so too.
What do you think of the two from Niigata?
But Kanto plus one is a little cool!
It's like the name of a technique.
Kanto Plus One.
Now let's hear the official opinion.
There is no unified organization of the regions to which our prefecture belongs.
In fact, the Niigata Prefectural Government doesn't even have an official answer as to what region it is.
Oh, you're saying that officially?
This issue is really bothering the idol side a little bit.
When we talked about going to Niigata for the campaign
I happened to be streaming it on youtube.
One of our members was going to Hokuriku, and he said something like "Niigata".
A fan commented that Niigata is not Hokuriku.
I got many, many comments like Niigata is not Hokuriku.
Like Niigata is not central Japan.
But I'm not sure.
I think you should clarify something.
Governor Hanazumi hasn't made it clear.
There is no clear answer.
By the way, Fuji TV affiliates are divided into various categories.
NST is in Hokkaido, Tohoku block, and Chubu block.
You can belong to various places.
It's like Niigata.
Yes, you could say that.
It can be like Kanto plus a high school like Niigata.
Special feeling
I think it would be great if we can cooperate with various places.
I agree.
But I'd like you all to write about it in the comments section of this Youtube video.
I'd like you to write about what you think of it in the comments section.
Or on Twitter.
I want you to fight.
Please use the hashtag "gata tube" and fight!
We'll look at it!
I'd like to decide what the gutter tube's answer should be.
Are all the NCGs in Kanto plus?
After this, we will investigate the problem of the character for "gata" in Niigata Prefecture.
I'm sure people outside of Niigata Prefecture can't spell "gata"!
Before that
Watch the video corner!
Yay!
Let's take a look at it right away!
Actually, I recently got married.
So I'm interested in the house.
I heard that you got married.
I'd like to introduce a house that would be perfect for you, Matsuo-san.
What are the elements that make it a good fit?
Yes, that's right.
There's a big park right behind the house, and there's also a big commercial center here.
There is also a large commercial center here.
And then there are the educational facilities.
There is also an elementary school.
A new JR station, Kobe Station, is being built.
The houses look very nice.
The exterior of the house has a nice appearance with white and cream colors.
The whole townscape here...
It's called "Euro Design".
From Aeon's commercial facilities to the apartments
And even the houses.
Everything is designed in a Western style.
Each house is spacious, isn't it?
That's right.
We have a rule called the "building agreement" in this complex.
We have a rule called the "building agreement".
We always build houses at least 2 meters apart from each other.
In Niigata, in the central part of the city, it's a bit tight on small lots.
In the city center of Niigata, some houses are built too tight on a small lot.
I actually brought half of them with me today.
Half of them?
It's a 100 yen stamp.
Will it work?
I'm sorry, it's no good.
Thank you for waiting.
Here you go.
It's nice.
It's on the lower lot to the northwest.
It's a model house.
The door is also stylish.
There's some kind of sensor on it.
Yes, it does.
This is the first time we've adopted this system.
We've installed a system that makes up the front door key by facial recognition.
It looks like a smart phone.
Yes, it is.
Warn.
Now it's unlocked.
Wow!
Yes, sir.
Yes, it does.
Huh.
Wow.
Stylish!
I can't believe we're in Japan.
Thank you very much.
This time, the interior.
This is a model house.
Everything is from IKEA.
Furniture and miscellaneous goods.
We've arranged them and coordinated them.
That's right.
It's really different.
It's spacious.
Two or three people can cook in a row.
I think it's possible for two or three people to cook side by side.
With a large kitchen and IH induction cooktop.
There's a sanctuary.
That's right.
It's very important to have a sunken kitchen.
These are vertical houses.
There are many people who are concerned about the lack of storage space.
But we have a lot of storage space in the kitchen area, so there's plenty of room.
However, the kitchen area is very well equipped with storage space.
There is also storage in the back.
There's also storage in the back.
By the way, this outlet in the middle is for power outage.
This is a dedicated outlet for the NF arm that generates electricity in case of power outage.
Yes, it is.
Stylish!
Wow.
Okay, that's nice.
I can't get three of these for my shachihata, but...
You know, this is a house that keeps getting more and more packed with people wanting to sign up.
It's got the latest technology with facial recognition from the time you enter.
It was a house of the moment.
This week's guests are Rika Mayama and Ema Sakurai from private Enishi Junior High School
Are there any prefectures that left a lasting impression on you?
Each prefecture has its own unique charms, but I'd have to say Hokkaido.
Hokkaido, of course.
Hokkaido is very special, isn't it?
The food is delicious, and I've recently become addicted to saunas.
There it is!
When I went to Hokkaido, the sauna was the best.
You first get hot in the sauna, and then take a water bath.
After that, you can take a water bath and have an outdoor air bath.
The temperature was so low that it was really nice.
I also went to Niigata.
By the way
The name of the Gokurakuyu...
Are you sure you want to go that far?
I went to the Meika branch of Gokurakuyu.I went to the Meika branch of Gokurakuyu.
I'm sorry to ask you to drive me just to take a sauna.
I'm going to join you in the cab.
By the way, I often go to Gokurakuyu in Meike.
It's a nice place with a TV.
By the way, Mr. Sakurai hasn't been all over the country yet.
I'm about to start.
Well, I haven't been all over the country yet.
I haven't been all over the country yet, but Fukuoka left a big impression on me.
The food is delicious.
I had tonkotsu ramen, Hakata ramen.
It was really good.
It left a strong impression on me.
Niigata also has a lot of delicious ramen.
You should try them!
I want you to try the "Five Greatest Ramen".
Have you ever tried them?
Yes, I have!
Back fat.
I had the back fat type.
How was it?
I thought it might be too much fat on the back, but it wasn't like that at all.
But it wasn't like that at all. It had a great soy sauce flavor.
Even the soup was delicious!
I can see it in my mind's eye now, can't I?
He put "Tubako" in the rakuboko cover and gave me no mercy!
How was it, Mr. Sakurai?
I could see it in your eyes.
Mr. Fukuoka, you tell me every time I'm not laughing.
Maybe he's making fun of me.
Like the guy who bought a tubular toy.
By the way, we're still in the middle of last week's and this week's Gattacchu.
Did you learn anything from Mayama?
The ramen you say is "slippery
You're forgetting everything
When I eat ramen, if I say "slippery
It's easier for my eyes to see it
Rakubo's senior is cute!
Here's the next topic!
Mr. Sakurai, please pretend to be a preggual!
Gatachum!
I have a question for the locals.
Do you know how to write "gata" well?
Do you know?
I don't know. Do you have any?
Can you write?
I'm always under pressure.
Only residents of Niigata Prefecture can write the character for "gata" correctly.
I've written it a few times. I can do it.
Like this, right? Like this, right?
It's a very unique way of writing.
I see.
I don't know what to do.
It's not white here.
It's a bit of a weird gutter character.
I'll get a correction item.
I jumped up a little bit.
And I don't know where to start.
It's true that "gata" in Niigata might not come to mind.
And I don't know the stroke order.
Well, I've prepared some drawing paper and pens, and I'd like you two to write on them.
You are free to start with "Niigata no Gata", aren't you?
The stroke order is fine.
Gata, right?
Are you kerning now?
Sideways.
Here!
He's looking at our chests.
What kind of education are you giving them?
Mr. Mayama, are you ready?
This?
Of course.
Then, Mayama, this is your "gata" character.
Wait a minute... that looks suspicious.
Where's Mr. Seto?
Close to hot water.
But Mr. Mayama's a bit...
That's not right.
What? You're not?
It's a little bit strange.
It's really bad.
What? Maybe I was wrong, too.
You have one too many.
What? Too many?
You see, at the top, on the left, there, there, there.
You mean that's the mistake? You don't need it?
I can write it, of course... but on a teacup, it's a gutter tube.
Of course you're right. It's natural to be able to write.
We've been doing this for two years. This way.
Oh! Gata from Niigata! That's my girl!
This way, Aika. You're the one who pushed it. You didn't need this.
It's all right if you just say "ah-ha". The old ones said they'd get a copy of the photo in 3 days.
Is that what you mean by "photo"? Is it like an abbreviation? Yes, abbreviations.
There are many people who write in abbreviated characters in Niigata Prefecture. They said it would be delivered this way.
No way! These are totally different characters.
Niigata Prefecture Niigata Prefecture
It's okay if you can't write it, because you can still receive your mail.
So it really takes a long time to go through the bank and all that.
It's like Niigata City, Niigata Prefecture. It takes forever.
Can you do that with this? Certainly, even in the public sector.
I wonder how it works now.
But there are people who use this as an abbreviation.
This person has posted a video on youtube about the character for "gata".
What is the kanji that was so hard to teach?
Gata in Niigata. I'm really sorry, Niigata people.
Is this kanji used anywhere other than in Niigata?
Surely there's "hi-gata"? Yes, but it's "hi-gata" again.
What? I don't even know where. What? What?
Look closely. If you look closely, you can see all three.
What's that on top? The broken kanji. I don't know how to write them in order.
Can't you just use white? There are four dots at the bottom too.
Can't the kanji be simpler? What's Japanese?
Hiragana, katakana, kanji, and now red Japanese again!
It's not only a pain in the ass, but the clasping shuttlecock is too loud!
I used to be very loud.
When I was a junior high school teacher, I felt sorry for them, even though I did it myself.
I was punished just for not having the last of the clasp feathers.
It was the worst... the teacher... the teacher...
I know you can't see the feathers, but I'll be careful from now on.
I did what you said you didn't want to do...
Kanji... well, I think it's time to loosen up on the clasped wings and kanji guidance.
I think it's time to loosen up a little more
What do you guys think?
By the way, I'm sorry to all the residents of Niigata Prefecture.
But please don't use Kanji anymore!
That's what they say, isn't it?
You're trying to pick a fight with me.
I'm getting a kick out of it.
By the way, the person who appeared in the video...
His name is Mr. Sakata, and he actually wanted to be a comedian.
He was Shizuru Murakami's partner at Yoshimoto's training school in Tokyo.
So you originally wanted to be a comedian, but now you're not?
That's right.
He is now a teacher and then a business owner and a YouTube star.
He's a very good speaker, isn't he?
He was a little angry.
But he did say he was sorry at the end, so I'll forgive him.
I guess there are a lot of people who feel this way.
It's true that many people, especially teachers, might be a bit miffed.
But you know what, the people of Niigata Prefecture should be proud of this.
Niigata is the most difficult prefecture in Japan!
Before we get to the announcement from Ebichu, please take a look at the video from last year's performance in Niigata.
Ebichu's video...
Good morning.
Yes, the first two days of the show have been postponed.
So today is the actual first day of the show.
I've got a lot of things to do and a lot of things to confirm.
I'm hoping that we can proceed without hesitation
I hope we can proceed without hesitation so that we can take on the final challenge of the show.
I'm sorry if I sounded a bit like a school teacher, but I'm really sorry.I said something a little bit like school... really.
The rehearsal...
There it is. I just saw it.
It's amazing.
Where are we?
Niigata!
Where's B?
Eguchi!
Niigata!
Fight!
Wow!
It's karaoke.
That's great.
I'm finally going to go now.
Wow, you must be thrilled.
Yes, I'm thrilled.
Wow, you must be thrilled a lot.
Hmmm, wow, it's been three years, right?
Hey.
Thank you very much.
To be continued on May 7?
Here is last year's video.
What you just saw is last year's video.
We are having our spring tour again this year,
It is called "Shiritsu Ebisu Chugaku Spring Tour 2023 100% Ebizumu" and we will be touring all over Japan.
We will be touring all over Japan.
Our performance in Niigata will be on May 7 at Niigata Terrsa.
We are looking forward to seeing you all.
I'll be waiting for you.
Sakurai, do you have anything to say about your enthusiasm?
I am going on my first spring tour this year,
I will be able to visit various places,
I want to make it a tour where I can feel that every performance was the best.
Have you really never toured before? What you just said.
It's my first time.
Haven't you been on about 5 tours?
I didn't feel like a newcomer from the moment I met you.
My first piece of advice is to give more of a rookie feel.
Well, gata team, next week will be our 100th broadcast.
Thank you very much.
So, that's all for now,
Shikapon and I are going out of the studio,
Shikapon and I are going on location,
Please enjoy the show as much as you can.
Thank you very much for joining us for the second week in a row.
Next week, Gattatube will finally reach its 100th episode.
We will go on a journey to collect gifts for our viewers.
Oh, hey, hey.
What's going on?
Some of you are asking for more gifts.
One of them.
Can you hear them? That's the voice in your heart.
I can hear it.
Here's what I'm going to say.
There is someone who wants to give you a gift for the gutter tube.
Where are they?
Wow!
A whole lot of seats!
That's right.
So much space!
Wow!
This is the theater! This is it!
Someone wants to present for the gutter tube.
Wow, there's someone in here.
Which way?
Huh?
Me?
Oh, no. Me?
Okay, I'll see you in a week.
Gattatube is on YouTube's favorite Type E channel.
You can also catch up on all the latest news!